A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Special Collections, Government Correspondence FA1527
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Special Collections, Government Correspondence
1969-1999
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA1527
1.52 Cubic Feet 4 letter document boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 2019 and 2020 by the Ford Foundation and ingested by RAC as Accessions 2019:181 and 2020:018.
Arrangement
Arranged as received from the Ford Foundation.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains copies of letters sent to government officials from Ford Foundation presidents and program officers. The collection also holds correspondence from government officials regarding Ford Foundation grants to governmental and non-governmental entities as well as Ford Foundation programs generally.
- State of Washington Department of Social and Health Services, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Trust for Public Land, San Francisco, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- US-Japan Parliamentary Exchange Program, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Vice President's Task Force on Youth Employment, Erik Butler, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Vanderbilt University Television News Archive, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Venture Fund - Grants to Colleges and Universities, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University - The Center for the Study of Public Choice, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Program for Professional Training in the Visual Arts - Fellowships and Scholarships, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Warren Wilson College, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Washington Center for Metro Studies, District of Columbia Citizens' Education, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- WHYY-Channel 12 in Philadelphia, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Wisconsin Center for Public Policy - Environmental Disputes in Wisconsin, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Young Women's Christian Association Building, Jersey City, New Jersey - Governor Kean, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Reproduction and Human Welfare: A Challenge to Research, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Resources for the Future Fisheries Project, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Rhode Island Housing Investment Fund, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- San Francisco Public Schools Commission Foundation, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Sangamon State University for Illinois Issues (state journal), 1976 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Savannah Landmark Rehabilitation Project, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Municipality of Metropolitan Seattle (METRO), 1973 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Southeast Alabama Self-Help Association (SEASHA), 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Southeast Development Inc., Subsidiary of South East Community Organization in Baltimore, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Southern Development Foundation of Lafayette, Louisiana, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Minority Labor Leadership Training Program, University of California (Berkeley), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Southwest Educational Development Laboratory in Austin, Texas, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- St. Louis Office of Manpower Planning, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Newark Community School of the Arts, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- North Carolina Manpower Development Corporation, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Nuclear Power Issues and Choices, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Oregon State Legislature - Oregon Public School Finance System, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Payout Requirement of Foundations, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Pennsylvania State University - National Study of State Plans to Organize and Support Postsecondary Education on a Regional Basis, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- University of Michigan - Population Studies Center, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Public Broadcasting Services, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- The Public Interest (Sent Out Under Bundy Letter), 1974 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Puerto Rican Legal Defense and Education Fund, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- PUSH Foundation for Project EXCEL, Chicago, Illinois, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- The Quality of Working Life Projects, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Native Americans Rights Fund (NARF), 1974 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Navajo Community College, Arizona, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Navajo Tribal Council, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Neighborhood Housing Services, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation, Washington, D.C. and Urban Homesteading Assistance Board, Franklin Thomas' Letter, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- New American Plays Program, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- New England Energy Policy Council, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- New Hampshire Conservation Commission, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- New Jersey Environmental Commissions, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- New York City Board of Education, 1973-1979 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Syracuse University Research Corporation, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Tax Reduction on Private Foundations, 1974-1978 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Tenant Affairs Board of St. Louis, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Texas Southern University - Master's Degree Program in Public Administration, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Supported Work File, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, 1976-1994 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, 1974-1996 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Agency for International Development (AID), 1974-1993 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Farm Credit Administration, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Federal Communications Commission, 1970-1995 (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Federal Maritime Commission, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Federal Trade Commission, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 61)
- General Accounting Office, 1974-1994 (Box 3, Folder 62)
- General Services Administration, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 63)
- Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Library of Congress, 1986-1994 (Box 3, Folder 65)
- National Archives and Records Administration, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 66)
- National Endowment for the Arts, 1986-1994 (Box 3, Folder 67)
- National Science Foundation, 1974-1998 (Box 3, Folder 68)
- National Endowment for the Humanities, 1981-1998 (Box 3, Folder 69)
- Office of Government Ethics, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 70)
- Office of Personnel Management, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 71)
- Overseas Private Investment Corporation, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 72)
- Peace Corps, 1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 73)
- Securities and Exchange Commission, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 74)
- Small Business Administration, 1985-1999 (Box 3, Folder 75)
- United Nations - Quasi-Official International and Non-Government, 1993-1998 (Box 3, Folder 76)
- U.S. Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, 1975-1987 (Box 3, Folder 77)
- U.S. Civil Service Commission, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 78)
- United States Information Agency, 1975-1997 (Box 3, Folder 79)
- United States Postal Service, 1973-1986 (Box 3, Folder 80)
- Carter/Mondale Planning Policy, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 81)
- Institute of Museum Services, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 82)
- U.S. Commission on Immigration Reform, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 83)
- The White House Initiative on Educational Excellence for Hispanic Americans, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 84)
- Department of Health and Human Services (Department of Health, Education, and Welfare), 1973-1988 (Box 3, Folder 85-86)
- Assistant Secretary of State/Secretary of State, 1972-1986 (Box 4, Folder 87)
- Department of State General Correspondence, 1974-1989 (Box 4, Folder 88)
- Department of State Overseas Schools Advisory Council, 1981-1985 (Box 4, Folder 89)